We need to talk about Palantir. Four
weeks ago, I made a video called four
stocks that are likely to 4x and one
stock that's not. And that one stock was
SpaceX and one of the four stocks was
Palantir. And SpaceX has fallen
substantially and Palantir has
well, at least in the last 24 hours
since I got back from vacation, done a
holy moly, that is impressive. I thought
for sure we would, you know, be able to
hold this 100-day moving average. I was
not expecting we would get all the way
up to 160 today, a 29% move. Really
insane. Part of me almost thinks a
little overdone that people have taken
on a little bit too much margin trading
back into this market now that Kevin's
back from vacation and Leo Fold has Leo
Folded. But, let's actually stick to the
fundamentals of this company. What is
this company worth? Is it still a
potential 4x? And what is it going to
take to get to that level?
Well, let's find out and see if there
are any red flags in this report. And
spoiler alert, there is a red flag in
the Palantir earning set. We'll talk
about that. Uh but, let's get right into
some of the notes that I'm making. So,
obviously, year-over-year growth
phenomenal at the company. 93%
year-over-year growth. Uh the commercial
side of business is actually growing
faster than government. If you jump in
over here, you can see government growth
last year was 78% and this year it was
uh 79%, which means the delta here is
1%. We still grew a nearly 80%, right? I
mean, just to like frame your mind about
it, you still doubled.
But, the pace you were growing at last
year, you really only exceeded by about
a percent this year for government. The
reason I bring that up is because I want
to show you where you're growing on top
of growing.
Commercial. Commercial is growing at
110%
while last year it was growing at 103%
which means there's been a 7 percentage
point acceleration in growth.
Now, why that matters is because if you
compare Palantir which is generating
about $2 billion worth of revenue in a
quarter here which is great. You know,
that's up from you know,
a billion dollars. I think it's first
time it had a billion dollar quarter was
this this quarter same quarter last
year. First time they had a billion
dollar quarter over here. Now we're
almost double that which is fantastic.
It's still a fraction of the $11 billion
of quarterly revenue that a company like
Salesforce is bringing in. But the
reason I bring in Salesforce isn't to
shill Salesforce, it's to show you the
difference.
Salesforce's revenue at $11.1 billion is
only is only growing at 13.2%.
The 7% growth on the growth of their
commercial contracts is almost half of
that 13.2%
right? So like the extra amount
commercial grew is basically half of the
growth all of Salesforce has and that's
on top of a double for Palantir. Maybe
that's excessively complicated the way I
framed it, but I think when you look at
these numbers it's just really important
to understand size-wise Palantir
revenue-wise is still a fraction in
terms of size compared to a Salesforce.
But in terms of market cap Palantir is
pretty dang well up there. Palantir's
market cap is sitting at $390
billion
where when I look at a CRM stock I'm at
less than half at 156.
And the difference is that growth rate.
People are doubtful about growth at
Salesforce and is that 13% actually
going to be robust and resilient?
Whereas at Palantir they are convinced
that growth is going to be resilient and
not only are they convinced growth is
going to be resilient, they think it's
going to keep going.
And I have to say as an investor in
Palantir
and Salesforce actually
slightly different levels on each of
these.
People are probably right about
Palantir.
The reason I say that people are
probably right about Palantir and this
is sort of an easier way in my opinion
to look at it is
there are some companies that reach out
to customers through sales teams and
they're like, "Hey man, can we offer you
a free demo? Hey yo, can we set you up
with a zoom call? We just need 5 minutes
of your time and then we'll do a
30-minute one after that and we'll send
you through the sales funnel."
Palantir doesn't pick up the phone for
their customers like new potential
customers unless those customers have
the potential of generating or spending
like 600 grand on the platform every
single month.
So if a company like UiPath who's trying
to you know put together robotic process
automation basically let's incorporate
LLMs into some form of automation system
which is different but you know you
could somewhat put it in a similar
category for the commercial contracts
you know putting data together in an
organized manner using LLMs to help
great. That's kind of kind of like the
foundry model at Palantir putting data
together and using
you know NLP right the keyword searching
basically old school which is what
Palantir was founded on. That has then
turned into the ontology platform
linking all of the data together which
then now incorporates AI Palantir the
whole thing that whole stack they now
call sovereign AI right that's the whole
package. So if at UiPath you've got
robotic process automated process
automation and you've got LLMs and then
over at Palantir you've got sovereign AI
These are two different packages, but
their goal is data efficiency and making
something happen. The difference between
the companies though, is UiPath is
sending cold emails going, "Yo, you
y'all want to give us a shot? How about
a free trial?" Palantir is like,
"Uh
we have so many people signing up who
want Palantir that we're actually taking
on fewer customers than ever before,
but we're selling our existing customers
more than ever before."
Okay, I just said up a lot. I'm going to
break this down for you. So, let me show
you some data on how I I come up with
this. Uh this is why it took me a day to
go through these earnings. You know,
like as much as I wanted to be live and
you know, just go through the earnings
live, I I actually kind of like really
enjoyed just brainstorming on this and
now I can give you these bottom lines.
So, take a look at this.
Uh Palantir has a a total commercial a
contract value of about 1.9 billion
dollars per quarter. If you divide that
by the commercial customers they have of
1,049,
that works out to an average of their
customers spending about $615,000
per month.
Now, their top 20 contracts are probably
more heavily weighted, but even if you
take out their top 20 contracts, you're
probably still looking at customers who
at bare minimum spend 250 to 300 grand a
month for software.
And unless you have the capacity or the
willingness to pay that,
Palantir is not even going to talk to
you. And the crazy thing about Palantir
is even if you had the willingness, they
have so much demand for their product
because of how they've marketed
Palantir, and I'll show you how they
pulled that off in a moment. It includes
terrorism. I know this is kind of a
weird thing to mention as marketing, but
they use it as marketing. I'll show you
just a moment. And and it really
helps us understand, "Wait a minute.
Okay, how do they do this?" But, watch
this.
These right here are their total
customer numbers. And I want you to
notice something.
Their quarter-on-quarter customer growth
rate is plummeting.
You literally went from a 13% customer
growth rate, you know, eight over here,
10% fine. So, you're between, you know,
8 to 13% over here, to now between four
and five and a half percent.
Now,
a bear is going to look at that and go,
"Bro,
that is horrible. Like, let's just exit
stage right. Why are we even here?
There's no point.
The company must be overvalued. The
company must be a scam. It's a rip-off."
And then, of course,
that's where Negan comes in. And I hope
you got your pants on.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh, actually, the real number that comes
in is what's called NDR.
And this has to do with net dollar
retention.
This is how much money you're making
compared to
the sales you were making last year to
your existing customers. So, for
example, if last year my existing
customers were paying me $100, and this
year they're paying me $111,
my net dollar retention would be 111.
Which, if you look at the first quarter
of 2024, is exactly what the NDR was for
Palantir. Now, I want you to think about
this.
The customer growth rate is falling.
What do you think is happening to NDR?
Is it also falling?
Falling would be bad, right?
No, it's actually skyrocketing.
In 2024, they were, you know, 111 to 120
over here on NDR. In 2025, they were
sitting at maybe an average of about
130%,
and in 2026 so far, they're sitting
about 150%.
So, this is an insane jump, and this is
probably the most prominent
W uh here from Palantir. This is really,
really impressive.
They are
being even more choosy than ever before
with their clients. Yet, they are
selling them more and more products and
services. Because remember, you're going
from uh the Foundry level to the
Ontology level to AI Palantir, and then
all together, we call all of that
together Sovereign AI. That's sort of
what the package is and how they market
it. So, when you see those words, that
that's what you're going to see.
The reason I bring this up
is
at first glance, when we see a customer
number decline, we have to ask
ourselves, "Okay, like that seems bad,
right?" But, you have to remember how
Palantir operates. What they're trying
to do is make sure that when customers
enter their boot camp, Palantir is
actually putting a massive investment up
front into sales and marketing basically
on, "Hey, is this going to be a good fit
for this company? Are we going to be
able to make this company money? Is this
going to be a win-win deal?" And the
hardest part is the beginning.
It actually becomes a whole lot less
costly for Palantir to service a
customer over time once they're locked
in. The lock-in effect is huge, but the
upfront, like teaching people how to use
the Ontology Suite, it takes time.
There's some effort that goes into this,
and actually setting up the data links
and the connections. You know, they can
actually data link into Salesforce. They
can literally take your Salesforce data,
link that in to the Palantir Sovereign
AI platform. It's brilliant.
Now, obviously companies like Salesforce
know this and they're trying to come up
with their own processes to sort of
build their own moat if they can, but
right now the one with the moat is
Palantir. So,
Palantir doesn't, in my opinion, have a
problem of finding new customers. There
are a lot of businesses that do have
that problem. Uh company like
ServiceNow, Salesforce, UiPath, they're
all looking for new customers. That is
the normal way of things. It's totally
normal. That's not a diss on them, it's
just normal.
Palantir has the opposite problem. They
actually prefer to just sell their
existing customers more because they're
making more money faster, but they do
slowly take in other cream of the crop
customers who are willing to pay a big
contract value because obviously that's
going to contribute to growth as well.
Now, when I talked about terrorism and
marketing,
take a look at this.
They literally say the following.
Karp,
like, we're supporting lots of
institutions in Europe, but the growth
sucks. I mean, clandestine institutions?
But, uh basically he's saying like, you
know, hey, like how much money is MI6
really going to be able to pay us? Or,
you know, a domestic three-letter
organization like the CIA. Like, there's
a limit. These companies have these
organizations have a budget compared to
companies that, you know, if we could
prove ROI, they'll spend more on our
software.
Well,
Karp argues that their work for
governments is because they want to
prevent terrorism. He literally says,
"Without our products, they would have
rampant terrorism and their problems,
their migration problems, and results
would be 10 times worse." So, he's
basically saying, "Look, without
Palantir, in uh like migration would be
worse, terrorism would be worse,
everything would be worse." Of course,
there can be no alternative to Palantir.
In my opinion, while some of this might
be true, I actually think this is how
Palantir markets.
The government side, even though it's
growing and making good money, is
actually the best marketing they could
ask for. It's brilliant because it clan
like he's mentioning this strategically.
If a clandestine institution with bad
growth trust Palantir with their data,
why shouldn't, I don't know, UPS with
their routing or the Mayo Clinic or a
law firm with their proprietary data,
right? And the big money is business to
business. that. That's where the big
money is going to be. So, that's where
Palantir has this really unique
advantage. They get to scoop off and we
talked about this in my video a month
ago as well. They get to shave off from
the cream of the crop and just pick the
customers they want. Nobody else really
has that. That's why I call it they get
to scalp customers. You know, the rule
of 40, people have asked me what this
means, let me just explain this really
quick, is basically just taking your
margin
and and your growth rate. So, your
EBITDA margin plus your growth rate, how
much you're growing at per year, and
then you add those two together. And
then you get this ideally rule of 40,
which is ideally you're growing at 20%
and your margin's 20%. Your EBITDA
margin's 20%.
Uh so, rule of 40 is really just
actually like a target percentage is
what it should be. And anything above
that is just considered good or great.
Uh and you know, they're sitting at 155%
which is obviously fantastic and it's
been growing. Uh and and you could see
that a lot of the contract deals they
have here, 73 deals completed at $10
million or more, they're fantastic. You
know, it's really uh guard railing
the token
uh self-pleasuring is really what I
think a good way to describe Palantir as
doing. They don't really care about LLMs
or which LLM you're using. They care
about, "Oh, well, instead of us using
NLP", which they actually reference in
here because that's those that's really
where they came from, right?
Uh here.
We had to work with NLP. That's natural
language processing uh basically
keywords, right? Those were the founding
days. We did not have AI available. So,
having AI available today is great, but
you could see that Karp and and he's
been in interviews. We've talked about
this on the channel before where he's
really anti people just burning tokens
and giving your intellectual properties
over to like a Claude or something else.
And this is really fair, but you need to
balance that Karp is going to say funny
things to bag on the token sellers like
the Clauds or the opening eyes. That's
why they want to be agnostic to this and
basically tell you that they are um
agnostic to uh what model uh you use. Uh
see for example, enterprises that are
not using Palantir are seeing their
token meters spinning endlessly just to
get slop. The token model may be working
for the labs, but it's not working for
anyone else.
That's a really big claim. And one of
the reasons for this claim actually
comes in the Kirkland example. So, right
here
they give a Kirkland and Ellis a law
firm example where they say that they're
working with Palantir.
And what used to take days for a lawyer
to analyze, discuss, and draft now
happens in minutes. And it wouldn't be
possible without ontology. All right.
Well, this is where we have to be a
little bit realistic even though, you
know, I we're bulls. We're invested, you
know, six-figure investors, not
seven-figure investors, six-figure
investors.
Um but um
you know, well when we look at
this as a feel like reasonable person, I
think it's reasonable to say that Claude
in fairness has a pretty good product
now. Where in like a legal case, you can
upload project files, and then you can
start new chats with fresh memories
citing those reference files in a
project, but resetting that sort of
memory or hallucination risk, right? Uh
well well still maintaining the context
of those documents, and that's really
valuable. And I think that's exactly
what Karp is
I don't want to say fearful of, but more
warning of. He's like, "Argh, these
these AI models, they're going to take
your data."
In theory, Claude can probably pretty
quickly whip up something that looks and
resembles Ontology inside of Claude. You
know, because really what's Ontology
going to be for a law firm? Well, it's
going to be dealing case templates,
letterheads, precedent structures that
we like to use, experiences we have with
local judges. This all gets sort of put
together in a structured format in how
we like to litigate our cases, right?
Now,
while that is a risk over a Claude, and
it's understandable Karp is fighting it
because if Claude does that, it is a
risk to Palantir,
I don't think Palantir's moat is going
anywhere. In fact, because
Palantir has so many people who want to
use Palantir who can't because they just
don't get an invite to use it cuz they
can't spend enough or there are just so
many people ahead of them in line,
honestly, the more companies like
Kirkland & Ellis are using Palantir, and
the more other lawyers are getting
excluded, the more Palantir just markets
itself for free. Because now it's like,
"Oh man, you're up against that law
firm? They use Palantir."
Right? And like, then you're like, "Oh,
I'm a law firm, too. I want I want to
use Palantir." You can't.
>> [laughter]
>> So,
massive moats, right?
All right. And and that's where when we
look on the cash flow statement, the
moat is not the cheapest, okay? So, just
to compare, you know, there is a premium
on on what you're paying in terms of a
cash flow yield. A cash flow yield is
really when we take your cash flow,
especially your free cash flow, which is
basically the same for Palantir, and we
divide it by your market cap.
So, in this case, they're making, you
know, $2 billion a quarter in
in in revenue.
And they're bringing about $2 billion or
a billion of that to the bottom line.
This is 6 months here, so $2 billion in
6 months.
Cash flow, they're bringing about a
billion dollars of cash flow to the
bottom line every single quarter, which
is really, really incredible. Because
last year they were at a billion dollars
of revenue. Now they're bringing a
billion dollars of cash flow in. You
know, the CapEx here is $22 million, so
you have no risk of this like
overspending on AI infrastructure.
You don't have that risk at all,
frankly. Because they're spending $22
million. Their cash flow is $2 billion
here in 6 months. So, in a 3-month
period, they're spending $10 million on
computers and infrastructure and GPUs or
whatever. And uh you know, they're
they're bringing a billion dollars to
their cash flow line. But the problem
with that is, let's say, you know, they
have $4 billion of annual cash flow and
they're a $400 billion company, that's a
cash flow yield of just 1%.
Salesforce is probably going to do about
$17 billion of cash flow, and they are a
$156
billion company, which is a cash flow
yield of 10.8%.
Now, we're going to do a valuation on
this in just a moment that that still
flatters Palantir. But let's be real,
there is a massive difference between a
1% free cash flow yield and a 10.8% cash
flow yield. And the reason for this is
the market in my opinion is probably
overvaluing the moat over here at
Palantir a little bit. You know, this is
this is a little rich. Uh I think they
got a little margin ran up here, but
that's okay. My end of the year price
target we talked about in the last video
was 192. I'll talk in just a moment
about how that's changed.
Uh
at Salesforce, this is probably so high
because the market is down waiting uh
Salesforce's growth because of
artificial intelligence, right? So,
artificial intelligence actually
potential is is hurting Salesforce's
valuation, whereas it's helping
Palantir's.
All right, so we'll get to that in just
a moment. So, let's make sure we've gone
through all the juice that I want to
cover here. So, we talked about this.
We've talked about the price target. We
talked about the video that I made.
Talked about Cloud. We talked about the
law firm. Uh
we talked about the decision logic
that's basically setting up uh you know,
your your structured data and your case
precedence if you're an attorney. The
models are a commodity, but the American
worker is not. This is marketing.
They're trying and they say this
regularly that hey, we're here for the
American worker. We stand for the
Americans, you know, whatever. It's
really a way it's it's a logical
fallacy. It's an appeal to patriotism.
Uh it's marketing. I'm not trying to
dish on them. I'm just saying know what
it is, okay? It's just like the whole
terrorism thing. It's great marketing.
And honestly, it works. You got to give
them credit where credit's due. They
actually made 3 cents of EPS from
investing in SpaceX. Quite interesting.
They are giving a red flag here about a
significant ramp in expenses in the
third quarter due to seasonality of new
hire starts
and new marketing initiatives, which are
probably marketing initiatives to their
existing customers, right? Because that
that's where a lot of their uh
dollar retention is coming from and it's
fantastic.
Um
which is great because if you already
have somebody on the system and you can
sell them more products inside the same
suite, you know, why not? They're
they're already in it. Uh okay, good.
So, what else did I write down here?
Okay, we talked about this. We talked
about Oh, yeah, here. So, uh a little
bit about how um
Oh, this is where they talk about how we
could swap if we want the LLMs. We've
talked about that already. Uh we've
already known that. There was the
terrorism thing. Just to make sure we're
not missing anything. Oh, yeah. People
aren't buying our product because we're
swinging the golf club correctly or
paying for the steak dinner. They don't
even invite us to dinners. This was a
little bit of a banger I wrote. They're
basically saying people are paying for
Palantir because we make an ROI for
people. They come to us because we make
them money. Talk about great marketing.
Oh, here it is. Switch out the models.
That was the swappable. They talked
about the LLMs a little earlier as well.
Okay, good. So, that uh that is the
earnings call.
Let's now go into the balance sheet and
then a forecast valuation for this
company.
So, on the balance sheet, they have
almost $10 billion of cash, technically
9.4.
They have $500 million in bills and some
lease obligations.
And
we we have What is this here? We have 2
billion uh Oh, wait. This is uh this is
the free cash flow. Right. So, basically
I've got $9 billion of free cash. That's
right here. Cash and cash equivalents,
marketable securities, less uh $500
million in bills. Fine. Call it roughly
8.9, $9 billion in cash
plus $2 billion of free cash flow every
6 months, 4 billion in a year. So,
really it's 9 billion plus 4 per year.
And that might be closer to 4.5 at the
end of this year or something like that.
This is a lot of money. and I actually
think they'll probably start
continuing some of their buybacks. If we
look at the cash flow statement right
now under the financing activities, we
don't see any buybacks.
And I think we're going to start seeing
that come back, you know, either
investing or financing. No stock
issuance and no buybacks, but I think
that'll come.
Uh you can also see the stock-based
compensation rose about 48%, which if we
go to the income statement is all just
increasing pricing power. The revenue
nearly doubled at 93-ish percent
rounded, but their costs were only up
53%. I wrote lol, that's major pricing
power. It is, because if you're growing
faster than your costs, that's pricing
power. You can also see that pricing
power in their operating expenses. Sales
and marketing growing at 39%. That's
like 1/3 of their growth rate.
Uh we've got G&A 19.6%
fraction of their growth rate. R&D 42.6%
fraction of their growth rate. So, all
of these right here suggest big PP.
Very, very big pricing power.
Uh and last year their earnings per
share were very, very low. So, for a
period of time this company actually
looked very expensive because their
earnings were really low. Right? I mean,
when they were making 4¢ a share,
5¢ a share, 7¢ a share,
the valuation's going to look high for
the company.
Now we're getting to half a buck per
quarter per share.
It's going to get to a dollar per you
know, it's going to get to $2, right?
Per quarter. That's pretty good. So, now
what we start seeing is the scaling out.
The scaling out, the buttering out of
all of the operating expenses.
And how does this actually look in terms
of a real valuation?
So, here are the numbers.
They are forecast to have a dollar and
57 of earnings per share at the end of
the year.
Their growth rate is expected to be
these numbers here, which averages out
to about 48% per year.
Their current PE ratio is 103.
So, obviously substantially above
Salesforce.
Uh
their that puts them at a price to
earnings growth ratio, right? If I just
divide these two into each other, of
2.157.
Now, for a forecast at the end of the
year, my prior forecast was 192. Using
now the updated figures with all else
being equal, I'm at 202 as a reasonable
price for this company at the end of the
year.
Now,
is it possible because they have so much
annual recurring revenue and an
incredible moat you could justify a
three PEG at a 50% growth rate? Yes. In
which case then you could justify a $235
valuation.
Now,
can this puppy still 4X in 4 years from
now?
Absolutely.
I mean, even if their growth in 4 years,
let's just run it really quick. Uh even
if their growth declines to 25%. We'll
do this live. Uh by 2030, right? $7.48
of earnings.
times uh 25% growth and we'll give them
a 2.69 PEG. That's still a $503
price target. If I go with a three PEG
at 25%
at 748 in earnings, I get a forecast
value of $561.
561 divided by what I paid last week at
118 is still a 4.7X.
Now, 561 divided by what you would have
to pay today at 165 is still a 3.4X.
So, and that's, you know, towards the
end of the decade.
So, tremendous upside here, tremendous
moat, massive pricing power. Their costs
are going to go up in Q3, but when you
really understand what's going on here,
this is a very, very different company,
and it's understandable why people are
paying a premium for this company and
their cash flow yield is as low as it
is. This is a very rare beast, and
honestly, I would not bet against them.
I would not Michael Bury Palantir, and I
have no qualms buying more in the 160.
This is a great company. Although, I do
think margin buyers really ran this one
up. But anyway, if you want more of my
fundamental analysis or my buy sell
alerts, anytime we
send alerts, or our courses on building
your wealth, or our daily Alpha
membership, make sure to join us over at
meetkevin.com, and we'll look forward to
seeing you in the next video. Goodbye,
and good luck.
>> Why not advertise these things that you
told us here? I feel like nobody else
knows about this.
>> We'll We'll try a little advertising and
see how it goes.
>> Congratulations, man. You have done so
much. People love you. People look up to
you.
>> Kevin Paffrath there, financial [music]
analyst and YouTuber, Meet Kevin. Always
great to get your take.